Guide to the Ruth Fulton Benedict Papers, 1857-1958
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Ruth Fulton Benedict Papers
1857-1958
Benedict, Ruth, 1887-1948
26 cubic feet (126 boxes), with an additional 5 cubic feet (25 boxes) of photocopies of originals for researcher use
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Personal and professional papers consisting of correspondence, diaries, notebooks, manuscripts and typescripts, articles, speeches, financial papers, reports, teaching materials, and photographs. Correspondents include Franz Boas with whom she studied and worked. Subjects include American Anthropological Association, Progressive Education Association, West Side Defense Council (New York City), Council Against Intolerance in America, American Association of University Women, American Folklore Journal, Mary Wollstonecraft, Indians of the American Southwest including Pima, Zuni, Dakotas, Sioux, and Shoshone, civil rights, and Japan and Japanese culture. Other items include her published and unpublished poetry; grant proposals; correspondence, clippings, and reports from field work, including her Mescalero trip, 1931-1932; and a draft of Margaret Mead's An Anthropologist at Work.
Biographical Note
Ruth Fulton Benedict, an American cultural anthropologist, was born in the city of New York in 1887 and died there in 1948. Her early years were spent on her maternal grandparents' farm near Norwich, New York as her father died when Benedict was just eighteen months old. Benedict's mother, Bertrice Shattuck Fulton (VC 1885), moved her family to St. Joseph, Missouri and Owatonna, Minnesota before becoming a librarian in Buffalo, New York when Ruth was eleven. In 1909, after graduating Phi Beta Kappa from Vassar College, in Poughkeepsie, New York, Benedict traveled to Europe with college friends. Following that, she was a social worker for a year, then spent three years teaching before marrying Stanley Benedict, a biochemistry professor at Cornell Medical School, in 1914.
In 1919 Ruth Benedict began taking courses, first at Columbia University with John Dewey and then at the New School for Social Research with Elsie Clews Parsons whose course in ethnology of the sexes kindled Benedict's interest in anthropology. Under the guidance of Franz Boas, Benedict received her doctorate in 1923 from Columbia, where she remained throughout her career. In 1948 she was promoted to full professor in the Faculty of Political Science, the first woman to achieve such status.
Benedict's fieldwork was done in California among the Serrano and with the Zuñi, Cochiti, and Pima in the Southwest. Student training trips took her to the Mescalero Apache in Arizona and Blackfoot in the Northwest. From her work in the field, several of her books were developed: Tales of the Cochiti Indians (New York: 1931); Zuñi Mythology (New York: 1935); and Patterns of Culture (Boston: 1934), which became a best seller and influenced American life in that it explained the idea of "culture" to the layperson.
During World War II, Benedict worked for the Office of War Information, applying anthropological methods to the study of contemporary cultures. A study of Japan was her final assignment. The outgrowth of her work on Japan for the OWI was her book, The Chrysanthemum and the Sword: Patterns of Japanese Culture (New York: 1946), which became a bestseller at the time and, ultimately, a classic work in the study of Japanese culture. It is still in print today.
Benedict died on 17 September 1948 at the age of 61.
Sources consulted for biographical data on Benedict:
Caffrey, Margaret. Ruth Benedict: Stranger in This Land. Austin: 1989.
International Dictionary of Anthropologists. New York: 1991.
Women Anthropologists. New York: 1988.
Scope and Content Note
The collection comprises the largest number of Benedict's known personal and professional papers and consists of correspondence, manuscripts of published and unpublished works, notebooks, lecture and research notes, diaries, photographs, financial papers, and clippings. The Benedict Papers served as the basis for two biographies: Judith Schachter Modell, Ruth Benedict: Patterns of a Life (Philadelphia: 1983) and Margaret M. Caffrey, Ruth Benedict: Stranger in This Land (Austin: 1989). Benedict's work on Japan is currently being revisited by scholars in Japan. Some recent publications are: Pauline Kent, "Ruth Benedict's Original Wartime Study of the Japanese," From "Japanese Behavior Patterns" to "The Chrysanthemum and the Sword," (Kansai: 1995).
Correspondence accounts for nearly a third of the Ruth Fulton Benedict Papers and includes a large number of letters from colleagues, friends, family, acquaintances, and students, along with many carbon copies of Benedict's responses, ranging from 1916 until Benedict's death in 1948. It is arranged chronologically, with some exceptions. Organizational correspondence is arranged alphabetically by organization name and includes the American Anthropological Association, New York Academy of Sciences, Council Against Intolerance in America, the National Research Council, and Progressive Education Association, among others.
From 1925 until 1940, Benedict was editor of the Journal of American Folk-Lore; consequently, there is a large series of correspondence relating to the journal (1923-1944). Correspondence from Franz Boas to Benedict covers the period 1922-1940. Another series of correspondence, formerly restricted by Margaret Mead, Benedict's original literary executor, is now freely accessible. This series includes letters to Benedict from some of her students, colleagues, and informants.
The collection contains many manuscripts of Benedict's published and unpublished articles, book reviews, speeches, and lectures, as well as numerous drafts of her unpublished biographical essay on Mary Wollstonecraft; a partial, unpublished book manuscript, "The Religion of the North American Indians"; and drafts and other materials relating to some of her books, including Race: Science and Politics (New York: 1940) and The Chrysanthemum and the Sword. During the 1920s, Benedict published sonnets, mainly in journals like Poetry, under the pseudonym of Anne Singleton. Many of her poetry manuscripts are located in the collection along with the stories that she wrote as a child and young adult. Poems published in Poetry or The Nation by Benedict were published as Anne Singleton; all other published poems were published in An Anthropologist at Work [AAW]. Box 120 contains material edited out of An Anthropologist at Work which are all mimeographs.
There are a large number of Indian subject files, deriving from Benedict's field work and other research, especially regarding mythology, as well as material from some of her students' field work. Numerous culture area files from her OWI days and correspondence and reports from her work for the government are in the papers; also her diaries (mainly from the 1920s) and notebooks; drafts of An Anthropologist at Work; and teaching and lecture notes. Some of this material is available online at Alexander Street Press's Anthropology Commons.
Photographs in the collection include many of Benedict and her family; photos of her taken by Stanley Benedict; the family farm in Norwich and Benedict's homes; and a few of Benedict in the Southwest. Some of these have been published in various works about her.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Margaret Mead served as Benedict's literary executor until her death in 1978. In a letter to Vassar's librarian in 1959, Mead noted that certain materials were still in existence, but not included in the collection: Benedict's letters to Mead and Mead's letters to Benedict (now located in the Mead Papers at the Library of Congress); and Edward Sapir's letters to Benedict. She further stated that most of Stanley Benedict's letters to Ruth were destroyed by her executor, Ruth Valentine, and no trace of her letters to Edward Sapir had been found.
Separated Materials
In addition to her personal and professional papers, a portion of Ruth Benedict's personal anthropological library was given to the Vassar College Libraries after her death by the executor of her estate, Dr. Valentine. At the time they were donated to Vassar in 1948, the decision was made to incorporate her books into the main library collection. In her letter dated 16 November 1948 to Sarah Gibson Blanding, then President of Vassar, Valentine expressed the hope that the books would be to those who read them "what they were to [Benedict]. Not only a record of others' research and thinking but a stimulus to go ahead and further ... enrich scholarship as a living force in the world."
Alternative Formats
Some materials from series XI and XV are available online at Alexander Street Press's Anthropology Commons.
Subject Headings
Names:
Mead, Margaret, 1901-1978; Wollstonecraft, Mary, 1759-1797; Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Organizations:
American Anthropological Association; American Education Fellowship; American Association of University Women; West Side Defense Council (New York, N.Y.); Council Against Intolerance in America; Journal of American Folklore; Progressive Education Association
Subjects:
Women--Diaries; Civil rights; Pima Indians; Zuñi Indians; Dakota Indians; Shoshonean Indians; Anthropology--Study and teaching; Anthropology--New Mexico--Field work; Women scientists; Anthropologists; Sioux Indians
Places:
United States--Social conditions; Japan--Social life and customs; Mescalero (N.M.)--Description
Document Types:
Correspondence; Diaries; Photographs; Poems
VCL Categories:
Anthropology and Anthropologists; Native Americans
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, March-April 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, August 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Estate of Ruth Fulton Benedict, shipped early in 1959 by Margaret Mead.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1916-1953; (Boxes 1-35)
- Series II. Diaries, Biographical Notebooks and Note Cards, and Family-Related Materials, 1912-1952; (Boxes 36-41)
- Series III. Financial Documents, undated; (Box 42)
- Series IV. Writings, 1905-1958; (Boxes 43-58)
- Series V. Grant Proposals, Consulting, 1931-1937, undated; (Boxes 59-60)
- Series VI. Teaching And Lecture Notes, 1930-1931, undated; (Boxes 61-69)
- Series VII. Student Papers and Other Miscellaneous Reports, undated; (Boxes 70-71)
- Series VIII. Miscellaneous Prose and Poetry by Others, undated; (Box 72)
- Series IX. Bibliography, undated; (Boxes 73-74)
- Series X. General Subject Files, undated; (Boxes 75-78)
- Series XI. Native American Subject Files, 1931-1941, undated; (Boxes 79-96)
- Series XII. Culture Area Files, [1934-1946]; (Boxes 97-111)
- Series XIII. U. S. Office of War Information [OWI], 1943-1948; (Box 112)
- Series XIV. Tests And Polls, undated; (Box 113)
- Series XV. Franz Boas (1858-1942), 1886-1958; (Boxes 114-116)
- Series XVI. Margaret Mead (1901-1978), 1909-1949; (Boxes 117-120)
- Series XVII. Edward Sapir (1884-1939), undated; (Box 121)
- Series XVIII. Photographs, 1857 - circa 1937; (Boxes 122-124)
- Series XIX. Maps, undated; (Box 125)
- Series XX. Realia, undated
Container List
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1953
  - CHRONOLOGICAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Correspondence to RFB, 1916-1925 (Folder 1.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, 1926 (Folder 1.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, 1927 (Folder 1.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, 1928 (Folder 1.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, 1929 (Folder 1.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Mar 1930 (Folder 1.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr - June 1930 (Folder 1.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Sep 1930 (Folder 1.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct - Dec 1930 (Folder 1.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb - June 1931 (Folder 2.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Aug - Dec 1931 (Folder 2.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Mar 1932 (Folder 2.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr - June 1932 (Folder 2.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Oct 1932 (Folder 2.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov - Dec 1932 (Folder 2.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Feb 1933 (Folder 2.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar - Apr 1933 (Folder 2.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May - June 1933 (Folder 2.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Aug 1933 (Folder 2.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep - Dec 1933 (Folder 2.11)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Feb 1934 (Folder 3.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar - Apr 1934 (Folder 3.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May - June 1934 (Folder 3.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Aug 1934 (Folder 3.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep - Oct 1934 (Folder 3.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov - Dec 1934 (Folder 3.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Feb 1935 (Folder 3.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar - Apr 1935 (Folder 3.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May - June 1935 (Folder 3.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Aug 1935 (Folder 3.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep - Oct 1935 (Folder 3.11)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov - Dec 1935 (Folder 3.12)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Feb 1936 (Folder 4.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1936 (Folder 4.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr - May 1936 (Folder 4.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1936 (Folder 4.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Sep 1936 (Folder 4.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1936 (Folder 4.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1936 (Folder 4.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1936 (Folder 4.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Feb 1937 (Folder 5.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1937 (Folder 5.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1937 (Folder 5.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1937 (Folder 5.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1937 (Folder 5.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Oct 1937 (Folder 5.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov - Dec 1937 (Folder 5.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1938 (Folder 6.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1938 (Folder 6.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1938 (Folder 6.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1938 (Folder 6.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1938 (Folder 6.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1938 (Folder 6.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Aug 1938 (Folder 6.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep - Oct 1938 (Folder 6.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1938 (Folder 6.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1938 (Folder 6.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1939 (Folder 7.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1939 (Folder 7.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1939 (Folder 7.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1939 (Folder 7.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1939 (Folder 7.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1939 (Folder 7.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Sep 1939 (Folder 7.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1939 (Folder 7.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1939 (Folder 7.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1939 (Folder 7.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan - Feb 1940 (Folder 8.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1940 (Folder 8.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1940 (Folder 8.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1940 (Folder 8.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1940 (Folder 8.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July 1940 (Folder 8.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Aug 1940 (Folder 8.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep 1940 (Folder 8.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1940 (Folder 8.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1940 (Folder 8.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1940 (Folder 8.11)
    - Correspondence to RFB, [undated] 1940 (Folder 8.12)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1941 (Folder 9.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1941 (Folder 9.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar - Apr 1941 (Folder 9.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1941 (Folder 9.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1941 (Folder 9.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Aug 1941 (Folder 9.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep 1941 (Folder 9.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1941 (Folder 9.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1941 (Folder 9.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1941 (Folder 9.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1942 (Folder 10.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb - Mar 1942 (Folder 10.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1942 (Folder 10.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May - June 1942 (Folder 10.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Aug 1942 (Folder 10.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep 1942 (Folder 10.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1942 (Folder 10.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1942 (Folder 10.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1942 (Folder 10.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1943 (Folder 11.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1943 (Folder 11.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1943 (Folder 11.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1943 (Folder 11.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1943 (Folder 11.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1943 (Folder 11.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July 1943 (Folder 11.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Aug 1943 (Folder 11.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1943 (Folder 11.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1943 (Folder 11.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1943 (Folder 11.11)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1944 (Folder 12.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1944 (Folder 12.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1944 (Folder 12.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1944 (Folder 12.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May - June 1944 (Folder 12.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July 1944 (Folder 12.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Aug - Oct 1944 (Folder 12.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov - Dec 1944 (Folder 12.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1945 (Folder 13.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1945 (Folder 13.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1945 (Folder 13.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1945 (Folder 13.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1945 (Folder 13.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1945 (Folder 13.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July - Sep 1945 (Folder 13.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1945 (Folder 13.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1945 (Folder 13.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1945 (Folder 13.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1946 (Folder 14.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1946 (Folder 14.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1946 (Folder 14.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1946 (Folder 14.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1946 (Folder 14.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1946 (Folder 14.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July 1946 (Folder 14.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Aug 1946 (Folder 14.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep 1946 (Folder 14.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1946 (Folder 14.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1946 (Folder 14.11)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1946 (Folder 14.12)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1947 (Folder 15.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1947 (Folder 15.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1947 (Folder 15.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1947 (Folder 15.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1947 (Folder 15.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1947 (Folder 15.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July 1947 (Folder 15.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Aug 1947 (Folder 15.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Sep 1947 (Folder 15.9)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Oct 1947 (Folder 15.10)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Nov 1947 (Folder 15.11)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Dec 1947 (Folder 15.12)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Jan 1948 (Folder 16.1)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Feb 1948 (Folder 16.2)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Mar 1948 (Folder 16.3)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Apr 1948 (Folder 16.4)
    - Correspondence to RFB, May 1948 (Folder 16.5)
    - Correspondence to RFB, June 1948 (Folder 16.6)
    - Correspondence to RFB, July 1948 (Folder 16.7)
    - Correspondence to RFB, Aug - Sep 1948 (Folder 16.8)
    - Correspondence to RFB, undated (Folder 16.9)
    - Correspondence re: RFB's "Science of Custom,", 1930-1939 (Folder 16.10)
    - Correspondence, undated; (fragments) (Folder 16.11)
    - Correspondence to and from others, 1943, 1951, 1953 (Folder 16.12)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1927-1930 (Folder 17.1)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1931-1933 (Folder 17.2)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1935-1939 (Folder 17.3)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1939 (Folder 17.4)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1940-1941 (Folder 17.5)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1942 (Folder 17.6)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1943-1944 (Folder 17.7)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1945-1946 (Folder 17.8)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1946-1947 (Folder 17.9)
    - Organizational Correspondence: General, 1947-1948 (Folder 17.10)
    - Academic Council of the YIVO, Yiddish Scientific Institute, 1946 (Folder 18.1)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1932-1936 (Folder 18.2)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1937-1939 (Folder 18.3)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1940-1946 (Folder 18.4)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1947 (Folder 18.5)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1947 (Folder 18.6)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1947 (Folder 18.7)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1948 (Folder 18.8)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1931-1948 (Folder 18.9)
    - The American Association of Scientific Workers, 1941-1948 (Folder 18.10)
    - American Association of University Women, 1942-1948 (Folder 18.11)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, New York, 1939-1941 (Folder 18.12)
    - American Committee for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom, 1939-1942 (Folder 19.1)
    - American Council on Education, 1944-1947 (Folder 19.2)
    - American Ethnological Society, Inc., 1941-1943 (Folder 19.3)
    - American Jewish Congress, 1945 (Folder 19.4)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1944-1945 (Folder 19.5)
    - American Psychopathological Association, 1946-1948 (Folder 19.6)
    - The American Scholar, 1939-1944 (Folder 19.7)
    - Character and Personality, 1937-1945 (Folder 19.8)
    - Conference on Education and Post-War Reconstruction, 194l-1942 (Folder 19.9)
    - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, 1940-1943 (Folder 19.10)
    - Council Against Intolerance in America, 1939-1942 (Folder 19.11)
    - Council for Pan American Democracy, 1940 (Folder 19.12)
    - Descendants of the American Revolution, 1939-1941 (Folder 20.1)
    - The East and West Association, l948 (Folder 20.2)
    - The Grolier Society, Inc., 1946-1947 (Folder 20.3)
    - The Kinsey Report, 1948 (Folder 20.4)
    - Laboratory of Anthropology, Inc., 1935-1939 (Folder 20.5)
    - Michigan Committee for Academic Freedom, 1940 (Folder 20.6)
    - National Research Council, 1935-1948 (Folder 20.7)
    - New York Academy of Medicine, 1946 (Folder 20.8)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1934-1942 (Folder 20.9)
    - New York Conference for Inalienable Rights, 1940 (Folder 20.10)
    - ONR, 1947-1948 (Folder 20.11)
    - Park West Neighborhood Association, 1948 (Folder 20.12)
    - Progressive Education Association, 1936-1938 (Folder 20.13)
    - Progressive Education Association, l939-1941 (Folder 20.14)
    - Progressive Education Association, 1942 (Folder 20.15)
    - The Service Bureau for Intercultural Education, 1938-1940 (Folder 21.1)
    - Society for Applied Anthropology, 1941-1947 (Folder 21.2)
    - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues (SPSSI), 1943-1948 (Folder 21.3)
    - University Federation for Democracy and Intellectual Freedom, 1938 (Folder 21.4)
    - Viking Fund, 1946-1948 (Folder 21.5)
    - Washington School of Psychiatry, 1945-1947 (Folder 21.6)
    - West Side Defense Council, 1942 (Folder 21.7)